KÁROLY LÓNICH

Full-Stack Web Developer

00 36 302573633

karoly.lonich@smartcoder.dev

smartcoder.dev

Vác, Hungary

github.com/kal40

in linkedin.com/in/karolylonich

@KarolyLonich



Certified software developer with 20 years electrical engineering background in industrial automation. I have experience in modern full-stack programming languages. I'm skilled in international projects, designing and commission complex automation systems and full-stack applications that makes me able to join any kind of team and contribute to the development of innovative solutions.

三 WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Myflix

https://myflix.smartcoder.dev, https://myflixapi.smartcoder.dev

A full-fledged full-stack web application. On the frontend with a beautifull responsive webpage with routing, rich interactions, several interface views, and a polished user experience. It was created with React and Redux for state management. On the backend a REST API will provide users with access to information about different movies, directors, and genres. Users will be able to sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of their favorite movies. It was created with Node, Express and using modern api structure. A MongoDB database is created to store all the data.

Meet App https://meet.smartcoder.dev

It shows upcoming full-stack meetups around the world. A serverless, progressive web application (PWA) with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique. The application uses the Google Calendar API and Serverless functions (AWS lambda) for the authorization server instead of using a traditional server to fetch the events.

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCES

Electrical and Control Senior Engineer

Sherbiny Engineering | March 2018 - February 2022

Designed Electrical Control Panels and specified instrumentation mainly for Oil & Gas and Petrochemical industry in the Saudi Arabian market. Commissioning support in Saudi Arabia.

Gas Turbine Controls Project Engineer

Baker & Hughs | June 2012 - March 2018

Led international projects of Gas turbine control system upgrades in Energy and Oil & Gas industry around the world

- Gas Turbine control software upgrade. Integrate gas turbine control with external utility systems. Designed the system control screens and network topologies. Configured Programable Logic Controllers.
- Created Visual Basic macros for large data handling in Microsoft Excel to reduce the project execution time significantly.
- · Led site surveys, studys, data collections and design review meetings with customers. Managed technical team during project execution.
- · Continuously communicated with customer's stakeholders and with our international engineering team. Prepared and led the customer witnessed Factory Acceptance tests and site commissioning support. My ability to effectively lead and communicate during these processes resulted in positive feedback from the customer which was a measurable value of our engineering team.
- · Mentored new team members and I have seen them develop and take on new responsibilities, leading to increased productivity, improved team morale, and ultimately, successful project outcomes

Control Cabinet Hardware Designer

Manufacturing Support Electrical Engineer

Maintenance Electrical/Automation Engineer

GE Oil & Gas | December 2009 - June 2012

GE Energy | June 2007 - November 2009

Samsung | October 2003 - May 2007

X SKILLS

Technical

JavaScript, React, Redux Node.js/Express.js

TypeScript, Angular

React Native

HTML5/CSS/SASS

Bootstrap

MongoDB, SQL

Git, Linux

Test Driven Development

Progressive Web Applications

AWS Lambda functions

Professional

Team player

Strong problem solver

Technology literacy

Mentoring

EDUCATION

Cloud Computing for Web Devs

CareerFoundry

2023 - ongoing

Full-Stack Web Development

CareerFoundry

2022 - 2023

BSc in Electrical Engineering **Budapest Polytechnic**

2000 - 2003

AT LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Hungarian (Native)





